<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R notes to myself</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on R notes to myself</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>calculating age</title>
      <link>/portfolio/calculating-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/calculating-age/</guid>
      <description>I have been playing with a new (not actually new, but new to R) dataset this week.
Successes:  I loaded the data in using read_csv. *** see ERRATUM below I fixed some weird data type assumptions.   The interview group is listed as 1s and 2s in the file so R thought those were integers. So I used as.factor to convert.  dataframe$variable &amp;lt;- as.factor(dataframe$variable)   read_csv did weird things with dates, importing them as factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fomo on #useR2018</title>
      <link>/portfolio/fomo-on-user2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/fomo-on-user2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been travelling for the last few weeks, first to a teaching conference at Duke called PsychOne, and then to the International Congress on Infant Studies (ICIS) in Philadelphia. There was a surprising amount of #rstats at ICIS which was awesome. Everyone is talking about reproducible science and preregistration and best practices that will improve our field. There is definitely another blog post needed to consolidate my notes from ICIS, but for now, I want to write about #useR2018 (a conference I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to go to).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curious</title>
      <link>/portfolio/curious-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/curious-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>What a treat it was to finally meet Charles Gray when she was in Sydney last week. She ran her R-Curious workshop for us and I picked up so many useful markdown tips.
 We worked from an Rmarkdown document in the workshop so we could edit the code and add our own notes but we could also how Charles had used specific markdown formatting to produce the document.
Because it was a “lets start at the very beginning” workshop, made me realise that when you teach yourself how to code, there are basic (but quite useful) that you don’t end up learning via osmosis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#SoDS18</title>
      <link>/portfolio/sods18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/sods18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Twitter is such a great R learning resource.
The people who follow the #rstats hashtag are so generous with their time. You can post a question/problem with the hashtag and someone will reply and try and help you within about 20 min. It is awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>git thinking</title>
      <link>/portfolio/git-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/git-thinking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The amazing &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/cantabile&#34;&gt;Charles Gray&lt;/a&gt; was extraordinarily generous with her time tonight trying to help be troubleshoot deploying this site (love R-ladies). I learned a lot about git.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first post</title>
      <link>/portfolio/2018-06-16-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/2018-06-16-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Woot! It works!!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>