<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R notes to myself</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on R notes to myself</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>insights from the Rmarkdown whisperer</title>
      <link>/post/insights-from-the-markdown-whisperer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/insights-from-the-markdown-whisperer/</guid>
      <description>I had the pleasure of attending Alison Hill’s RMarkdown workshop in Canberra on Monday and I came away with so many tips and tricks! It was brillant.
Alison covered A LOT over the course of the day. I learned lots of the power of yaml, how to create parameterised reports, and how to make a package that contains customised .Rmd templates. Each of those topics are blogposts for another day, but my favourite bit was making a beautiful Academic theme blogdown site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mutate &#43; if else = new conditional variable</title>
      <link>/post/mutate-and-if-else-to-create-new-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mutate-and-if-else-to-create-new-variables/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I keep googling &lt;a href=&#34;https://rstudio-pubs-static.s3.amazonaws.com/116317_e6922e81e72e4e3f83995485ce686c14.html#/1&#34;&gt;these slides&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;@daranzolin&#34;&gt;David Ranzolin&lt;/a&gt; each time I try to combine mutate with ifelse to create a new variable that is conditional on values in other variables.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>customise your R experience</title>
      <link>/post/customise-your-r-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/customise-your-r-experience/</guid>
      <description>Would you like RStudio to show you a random The Good Place quote, spoken by a ASCII animal along with some random message of praise/encouragement each time you start a coding session or restart R?
Of course you would!!!
how to customise your .rprofile You will need to install the following packages:
 usethis goodshirt cowsay praise  Use usethis to open your .rprofile file usethis::edit_r_profile() Copy and paste this text into your .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pivoting</title>
      <link>/post/pivoting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/pivoting/</guid>
      <description>Cute #rstats monster art by the amazing Allison Horst.
I have been using gather() and spread() a lot lately. I’m on the tidy data train; long data is essential for ggplot etc, but sometimes you want to do calculations row wise, which is kinda complicated.
For example, this week Matilda and I were working with her language/locomotion data and we were looking at the number of action-directed, affirmative, and descriptive responses that parents make to their infants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>making memes in R</title>
      <link>/post/making-memes-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/making-memes-in-r/</guid>
      <description>I having been prepping for my lightning talk at the R-Ladies Sydney Birthday this weekend and learning about all the packages that you can use to make memes in R. I’m going going to talk about my favourite option (which is the memery package), but here is what I learned about other packages.
Option 1: memer The memer package by Sam Tyner is a tidyverse compatible package that allows you to replace text in popular memes with your own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>apa figures</title>
      <link>/post/apa-figures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/apa-figures/</guid>
      <description>As I write my first paper reporting data analysis coming out of R (woot!!!), here are some notes summarising all the googling I have done this morning about how to produce APA style figures in ggplot.
  via GIPHY Load libraries Start by loading tidyverse to get ggplot, here to make finding the data easy, and papaja to get the theme_apa() function.
library(tidyverse) library(here) library(papaja)  Read in data plotdata &amp;lt;- read_csv(here(&amp;quot;plotdata.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>blogdown</title>
      <link>/post/blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/blogdown/</guid>
      <description>There has been lots of talk about blogdown on #rstats Twitter recently and people have been talking up the Hugo “Academic theme”.
I want to give it a go to update my lab website, so thought it might be a good idea to pull together all the useful links I’ve seen recently into one place.
Alison Hill I used Alison’s blog post when I first set up this blog. It looks like she has updated the post recently, so it is probably still a good place to start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>newposttest</title>
      <link>/post/newposttest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/newposttest/</guid>
      <description> I think I have broken hugo testing whether this works
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rm anova options</title>
      <link>/post/anova-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/anova-options/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been analysing some future thinking data and playing around with packages that can do repeated ANOVA (I know, I should do LMM). There is more than one way to skin a cat and the differences come down to two things.
the intuitiveness of the function arguments the readibility of the output  Some checks to do before you start - all of these packages assume that you within and between subjects variables are factors, but also that your participant id is a factor</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Three Things</title>
      <link>/post/just-three-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/just-three-things/</guid>
      <description>I love me a good #rstats screencast. David Robinson has been screencasting his #TidyTuesday efforts for the past few months and while it is GREAT to watch a master at work, I just don’t have time to watch someone code for an hour, in order to extract a handful of tips.
So when I saw Nick Tierney tweet about posting short videos that contain Just Three Things, I thought “that is a GREAT idea”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infinite moon reader</title>
      <link>/post/infinite-moon-reader/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/infinite-moon-reader/</guid>
      <description>I saw an intriguing tweet this afternoon.
🧙 ♂️Live preview for R Markdown!
TIL that you can have a live preview of your #rstats Markdown docs!
Just use the infinite_moon_reader function from the xaringan package.
It works for all single-HTML-file outputs and even comes with a pre-made RStudio Addin! — Jozef Hajnala (@jozefhajnala) January 2, 2019   When Charles was visiting for #RCurious in June, she had written her slides in xarigan and was raving about infinite moon reader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how to add a gif</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-add-a-gif/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-add-a-gif/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes your plot needs a celebratory gif.
I have just finished the vizwhiz module for #RYouWithMe and to top off the series I worked out how to add an RLady Wizard to our final plot.
Just so I’ll remember for next time, here is a step by step how to…
 how to add a gif to your ggplot Install the magick package and load it with ggplot. Install and load the beepr package too so you can have RStudio beep at you when it has finished rendering your gif (it can take a long time).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how to use the `here` package</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-use-the-here-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-use-the-here-package/</guid>
      <description>I’m still working on getting my head around where R thinks we work and how to tell it where my stuff lives (aka working directories).
On twitter yesterday Alison Hill, Adam Gruer, Zoe Meers and Irene Steves helped me sort out my issues with here.
hi #rstats friends, how do YOU use the here package? I thought I had my head around it but I&#39;m doing something wrong. Here my markdown lives within the “markdown” folder, so I set here to the “data” folder, call read_csv(here(“datafile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>things i googled this week</title>
      <link>/post/things-i-googled-this-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/things-i-googled-this-week/</guid>
      <description>How would we learn R if not for google? Here are some things I googled this week (and mostly not for the first time).
1. how to install a package from github. 95% of the time, packages I want are on CRAN and I can just use the install.packages function to install them.
install.packages(&amp;quot;nameofthepackage&amp;quot;)  Occasionally though, I see something cool and new on Twitter and need to install from github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing about LMM</title>
      <link>/post/writing-lmm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/writing-lmm/</guid>
      <description>Learning new things is HARD. Stats methods are particularly hard because it not just about running the test. You have to…
 learn when to run the test learn how to run the test learn how to interpret the test AND learn how to write about the results of the test  Part of what makes this learning hard is that our research methods training has drummed into us that there is a RIGHT WAY TO DO IT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>let me count the ways</title>
      <link>/post/let-me-count-the-ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/let-me-count-the-ways/</guid>
      <description>psycho package ANOVA Recap EMG + psycho psycho steps THOUGHTS about psycho  Likelihood Ratio Tests Lets go hiking EMG + LRT THOUGHTS about LRT  lmerTest package is LRT anticonservative? EMG + lmerTest THOUGHTS about lmerTest  Next: “how to write about LMM”   When we want to learn how to do something new in R, we all start by googling it. Having worked out simple ANOVA, next on my list is repeated measures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>where is here?</title>
      <link>/post/where-is-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/where-is-here/</guid>
      <description>As I add new projects to my rstats portfolio and work collaboratively on projects with students the issue of working directories is becoming more and more complicated. Not really understanding how working directories and file paths actually work, I have been relying on the beginner logic…
 Everything will be just fine as long as you keep your datafiles in the same folder as your .rmd file
   via GIPHY I aspire to have organized folders that Jen Thompson would be proud of, but that is going involve getting my head around directories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gather spread unite separate</title>
      <link>/post/gather-spread-unite-separate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/gather-spread-unite-separate/</guid>
      <description>This content has appeared before in a dirty data post, but I still find myself googling these functions. So they deserve a post of their own. The tidyr package has several functions that allow you to reshape your data. They are surprisely useful; I have found myself gathering a lot, mostly to get data from &amp;ldquo;SPSS format&amp;rdquo; into something that ggplot will handle. I have also discovered the flexibility with which you can spread the data on a particular variable, do a set of computations, and then gather it back for plotting&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>next up anova</title>
      <link>/post/next-up-anova/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/next-up-anova/</guid>
      <description>In the kind of research that we do, t-tests can only take you so far. Most often we design factorial experiments where we are interested in both main effects and interactions. Because we work with infants and young children, who are both expensive to recruit/test and notoriously variable in their behaviour, we try to design experiments that use within-subjects designs; each child gives us more than one data point and we need to use repeated-measures analyses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>more wrangling tips</title>
      <link>/post/more-wrangling-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/more-wrangling-tips/</guid>
      <description>It is definitely true that it takes much longer to get your data ready for analysis than it does to actually analyse it. Apparently up to 80% of the data analysis time is spent wrangling data (and cursing and swearing).
Did you know up to 80% of data analysis is spent on the process of cleaning and preparing data? - cf. Wickham, 2014 and Dasu and Johnson, 2003
So here is an excellent approach to data wrangling in #rstats https://t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>me</title>
      <link>/about/me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/me/</guid>
      <description>I am a developmental psychologist in the School of Psychology at UNSW Sydney. My research investigates age-related changes in learning, memory, and emotion understanding in infants and preschoolers. Babies and kids tend not to tell you what they remember or understand, so we use method like eyetracking and psychophysiology to record subtle changes in their behaviour. These methods produce a LOT of data.
This blog is a record of my R learning journey as I venture into new data wrangling and analysis approaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a friendly t-test example</title>
      <link>/projects/a-friendly-t-test-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/a-friendly-t-test-example/</guid>
      <description>This dataset is from the car package and includes recall scores as a function of encoding conditions.
friendly &amp;lt;- read.csv(&amp;quot;friendly.csv&amp;quot;) class(friendly) ## [1] &amp;quot;data.frame&amp;quot; Explore the friendly data Get some summary stats from skim() including mini-histograms
skim(friendly) ## Skim summary statistics ## n obs: 30 ## n variables: 2 ## ## ── Variable type:factor ─────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────── ## variable missing complete n n_unique top_counts ## condition 0 30 30 3 Bef: 10, Mes: 10, SFR: 10, NA: 0 ## ordered ## FALSE ## ## ── Variable type:integer ────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────── ## variable missing complete n mean sd p0 p25 p50 p75 p100 hist ## correct 0 30 30 34.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>testing out t-tests</title>
      <link>/post/testing-out-t-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/testing-out-t-tests/</guid>
      <description>I was trying to work out how to do t-tests using my own data and the lsr package but ended up working with Dani’s AFL data from her book while trying to work out why R insisted that my outcome variable wasn’t numeric (it definitely was). Turns out that the lsr package doesn’t deal well with tibbles (which are created by default when you use read_csv to get your data) but if you use read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>using R for analysis</title>
      <link>/post/using-r-for-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/using-r-for-analysis/</guid>
      <description>I am feeling more confident about my resolution to get rid of Excel and only use R for data wrangling and visualisation. Next steps&amp;hellip; analysis.
I&amp;rsquo;m starting simple (I presume) with t-tests. Mostly commonly I want to determine whether there is a difference in the performance of independent groups of kids, or a difference between kids&amp;rsquo; performance on two different conditions, or whether kids are just guessing (i.e. whether their performance differs significantly chance).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>creating data using rep()</title>
      <link>/post/creating-data-using-rep/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/creating-data-using-rep/</guid>
      <description>The frequency with which my data is missing important information when it gets to R is a bit embarrassing. I&amp;rsquo;m sure as I learn what kind of information R needs I&amp;rsquo;ll get better at this but for the moment using functions like rep() to create variables like trial number or block has been super useful.
Alison Smith has a great blog called Very Statisticious and her post about simulating data is super helpful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use map to read many csv files</title>
      <link>/post/use-map-to-read-many-csv-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/use-map-to-read-many-csv-files/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dipping my toes in purrr here and replicating options from a &lt;a href=&#34;https://serialmentor.com/blog/2016/6/13/reading-and-combining-many-tidy-data-files-in-R&#34;&gt;super useful blog post&lt;/a&gt; I found by &lt;a href=&#34;@clauswilke&#34;&gt;ClausWilke&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I don’t like cats much</title>
      <link>/post/i-don-t-like-cats-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/i-don-t-like-cats-much/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t love cats. I am not a member of @RCatLadies. So the fact that Tidyverse packages for dealing with factors and functional programming have cat-related names (forcats and purrr) does not endear them to me.
I knew there was a time when I would encounter an R problem that needed the power of for loops, so when I asked the Twittersphere whether there was an alternative (hopefully a tidyverse one) that would allow me to avoid loops a little longer, I was a bit disappointed to hear that it is the purrr package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lesser known stars of the tidyverse</title>
      <link>/post/lesser-known-stars-of-the-tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/lesser-known-stars-of-the-tidyverse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;@robinson_es&#34;&gt;Emily Robinson&lt;/a&gt; has just joined DataCamp and writes a great blog called www.hookedondata.org. She talked at the 2018 New York R conference recently and shared some of her favourite (less well known) stars of the Tidyverse. Here are her slides www.tiny.cc/nyrtalk and my notes&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dirty data</title>
      <link>/post/dirty-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/dirty-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been doing lots of data wrangling recently and decided a needed a quick rundown of data cleaning in R. Turns out www.DataCamp.com has a course called exactly that. Here are notes on useful things I learned.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hotkeys</title>
      <link>/post/hotkeys/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hotkeys/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are some commands that as I get more and more familiar with Rstudio I find myself typing again and again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cooking with datapasta</title>
      <link>/post/cooking-with-datapasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cooking-with-datapasta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another day&amp;hellip; another data set. This time I am trying to get EMG data from LabChart into R. LabChart is the software we use to record EMG data and do the first steps of data cleaning/processing. At the moment a good chunk of the cleaning process involves Excel macros, so my goal is to replicate what we have traditionally done in Excel in R, so that it is more automated and more reproducible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>calculating age</title>
      <link>/post/calculating-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/calculating-age/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been playing with a new (not actually new, but new to R) dataset this week.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fomo on #useR2018</title>
      <link>/post/fomo-on-user2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/fomo-on-user2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been travelling for the last few weeks, first to a teaching conference at Duke called PsychOne, and then to the International Congress on Infant Studies (ICIS) in Philadelphia. There was a surprising amount of #rstats at ICIS which was awesome. Everyone is talking about reproducible science and preregistration and best practices that will improve our field. There is definitely another blog post needed to consolidate my notes from ICIS, but for now, I want to write about #useR2018 (a conference I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to go to).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curious</title>
      <link>/post/curious-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/curious-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;What a treat it was to finally meet &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/cantabile&#34;&gt;Charles Gray&lt;/a&gt; when she was in Sydney last week. She ran her R-Curious workshop for us and I picked up so many useful markdown tips.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#SoDS18</title>
      <link>/post/sods18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sods18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Twitter is such a great R learning resource.
The people who follow the #rstats hashtag are so generous with their time. You can post a question/problem with the hashtag and someone will reply and try and help you within about 20 min. It is awesome.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>git thinking</title>
      <link>/post/git-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/git-thinking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The amazing &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/cantabile&#34;&gt;Charles Gray&lt;/a&gt; was extraordinarily generous with her time tonight trying to help be troubleshoot deploying this site (love R-ladies). I learned a lot about git.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first post</title>
      <link>/post/2018-06-16-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-06-16-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Woot! It works!!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/2018-08-30-hidden-stars-of-the-tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-08-30-hidden-stars-of-the-tidyverse/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>